<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Big Data Ethics</title>
    <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Big Data Ethics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joecoelhosj.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dictionaries in Python for Textual Data</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/pythondictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/pythondictionary/</guid>
      <description>Python provides a powerful natural language processing toolkit for handling textual data. The toolkit has functions for operations like tokenizing as well as parts-of-speech identification, n-gramming, etc. In addition it contains a corpora of useful datasets like &amp;lsquo;stopwords&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;synonyms&amp;rsquo;, etc.
Natural Language ToolKit (NLTK) To install the NLTK library, run the following at the system command prompt (terminal window):
pip install nltk  To download the NLTK Corpora, run the following statements at the Python Prompt:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation using SimPy</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/simpy-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 22:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/simpy-example/</guid>
      <description>Coffee shop scenario Coffee shops are generally a popular place to hangout. Starbucks, Colectivo, Anodyne, Stone Creek, etc. are some of the sought-after coffee shops in Milwaukee. It is not just the rejuvenating coffee that attracts customers, but the ambience draws people who want to read, work on their laptops, write, do some deep thinking, carry on conversation, or just relax. However, sometimes getting a cup of coffee can take a long wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataset Repository List</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/datasets/</guid>
      <description>Data is called the new &amp;ldquo;black gold&amp;rdquo; and is being monetized through different avenues. Recommender Systems, Machine Learning operations, Data Mining, Pattern Recognition, etc. require data. Privacy concerns has limited the accessibility of user generated data. However, there are still a few places where data can be freely got for research purposes.
Free Twitter Datasets Curated Twitter Data
Twitter DataStream Archives
Conference on Web and Social Media &amp;ndash; Dataset Sharing Service</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IEEE BigData Congress 2018</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/post/ieeebigdata2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 11:25:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/post/ieeebigdata2018/</guid>
      <description>The IEEE 2018 World Congress on Services held in San Francisco, CA during 2-7 July was a jamboree of sorts. It included the BigData Congress as well as Cloud, Edge, ICCC (Cognitive Computing), ICIOT (Internet of Things), ICWS (Web Services) and SCC (Services Computing) parallel sessions. I was privileged to present a work-in-progress paper related to personalization of travel recommendations using social media analysis in one of the BigData sessions. The basic concept of the recommendation system is to mine a user&amp;rsquo;s social media content (like twitter feed) and use that data to predict the user&amp;rsquo;s places of interest categories (like museum, parks, restaurants, buildings, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog using Hugo on Github</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/hugoblog-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 16:59:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/hugoblog-github/</guid>
      <description>How to Create a Personal Blog on Github using Hugo Github is a popular free static hosting service for personal and project pages. Hugo is a framework for building websites. More information about Hugo can be got at https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/
The Hugo website also has instructions for creating a personal website on Github. Instructions can be got at https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/
Step 1: Download Resources and Setup Directories  Download and intall Git (https://gitforwindows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Identifying News Article Sentiment</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/newsarticlesentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 23:38:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/newsarticlesentiment/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment Analysis Identifying the sentiment of a news article or tweet can be useful in many ways. For example, sentiment of news about stock or the economy or sentiment of tweets of a user regarding the stock market might correlate to movements in the stock market. These in turn can be used for personalizing recommendations or for predicting market sentiment. In this brief tutorial we will look at how news article sentiment can be guaged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy in a Connected World</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/post/facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 09:29:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/post/facebook/</guid>
      <description>Facebook is in the news for all the wrong reasons these days1. And at the center of their troubles is the often discussed issue of privacy. Digital technology has evolved from being merely computing machines to connected machines. First it was the Intranet that connected computers togethers in a local space. Then came the Internet bringing with it global connectivity. Communication became easier, faster and more convenient. Benefits of this new technology began to flow from the workspace to the personal space of individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling data in JSON and CSV formats</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/twitter-python-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 09:16:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/twitter-python-3/</guid>
      <description>Python includes packages for handling data in JSON and CSV formats. JSON stands for JavaScript Object Notation format. It is basically a key-value pair store. CSV stands for Comma Separated Variables. It is a list of data values separated by comma (or some other delimiter).
If you open the tweets.txt file saved in the previous session, you will notice that each line is in the JSON format. Each tweet is enclosed in braces {}, and within the braces are key:value pairs separated by commas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting Streaming Twitter Data</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/twitter-python-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 09:15:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/twitter-python-2/</guid>
      <description>Twitter no longer provides free access to all streaming tweets (Twitter Firehose). However, it does allow access to &amp;ldquo;some&amp;rdquo; streaming tweets in real time based on filters. In the code below all tweets having &amp;lsquo;Las Vegas&amp;rsquo; in them will be filtered. [More: http://tweepy.readthedocs.io/en/v3.5.0/streaming_how_to.html]
One needs to be aware of the rate limits imposed by Twitter while accessing their feeds. It is always advisable to include pauses in code execution to ensure that the rate limits are not violated OR include error handling routines that can trap rate violation errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Reading Twitter Data in Python</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/twitter-python-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 23:38:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/twitter-python-1/</guid>
      <description>Social Media Analysis Social media has become the go-to place for information and opinions. Social media can be mined to gauge sentiment, analyze opinion, identity interests, locate concerns, and so on. Facebook, Pinterest, Instagram, Twitter, Google+ are some social media platforms. Among them, Twitter data is public and can be mined relatively easily.
First of all you need to obtain access codes from Twitter to be able to mine Twitter data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 23:29:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Technology is directing the evolution of human beings. Digital devices like smartphones have become an extension of the human body. People rely a lot on such tools not just for information but as a supplement to their memory and even intelligence. Could such dependency result in decreased use of the brain and thereby result in lowered brain &amp;ldquo;capacity&amp;rdquo; over generations? Of course, there are those involved in making this technology possible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 09:51:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Joseph Coelho, a graduate student in the Department of Mathematics, Statistics and Computer Science at Marquette University, Milwaukee, WI. My interests are in Database Systems, Data Science, Machine Learning, and the Ethics of Machine Learning &amp;amp; Big Data Applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/regex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joecoelhosj.github.io/tutorial/regex/</guid>
      <description>The Power of Regular Expressions
Every so often there comes a need to process textual data. It could be something like splitting a sentence into words, or validating input data against a given format, or searching for patterns in a text. Regular expressions are powerful when it comes to manipulating textual data.
Pythion comes with the regular expression library called re. To use it one would need to import it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>